<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sam Adesoga&#39;s Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sam Adesoga&#39;s Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 13:27:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do you need to learn SQL as a tester?</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/why-do-you-need-to-learn-sql-as-a-tester/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 13:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/why-do-you-need-to-learn-sql-as-a-tester/</guid>
      <description>In the last 5 years or so, we have been training and mentoring Software Testers and Business Analysts and as part of the mentoring session, I ask about their experience of interviews; generally I am looking for the sort of questions the mentees are being asked and more importantly what answers were provided to the interviewers. My observations in recent years is that there is an increasing demand for manual testers with technical skills and knowledge of databases is one that sits high on the list of technical skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should API test and UI Acceptance Tests be written in the same programming language?</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/api-tests-and-ui-test-should-be-written-in-same-programming-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 22:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/api-tests-and-ui-test-should-be-written-in-same-programming-language/</guid>
      <description>I have written in my previous blog about how we need to distribute our tests across the testing pyramid for reasons which i have explained in the previous blog. This particular post is focussed on how we ought to design our tests across the higher levels of abstractions which includes the UI test and API tests.
For the purpose of the blog, I would be using a case study of team that writes its UI Acceptance tests in protractor (Javascript) and the API tests in Java using RestAssured library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading CSS files using &#34;Shrine&#34; gem</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/uploading-css-files-using-shrine-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 22:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/uploading-css-files-using-shrine-gem/</guid>
      <description>I have recently switched from carrierwave to shrine in my Rails app and i thought i follow the advice of Alan Richardson, saying when you learn something new, irregardless of how trivial it might seem to you, share it and save someone else that headache.
So in the Yangah application, we upload a number of files to amazon s3 which include images, font files and css files for these fonts. However, i have found that with shrine, out of the box it was not able to correctly set the mime type for the uploaded file on s3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing an Asynchronous System - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/testing-an-asynchronous-system-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 13:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/testing-an-asynchronous-system-2/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I would like to consider how to write automated tests for negative scenarios for a system built using an asynchronous / event driven architecture. In my previous post, i have mentioned, that these systems are peculiar because the effect of the &amp;ldquo;write&amp;rdquo; actions are not immediately stored in the persistence layer of the application under test.
As an example, in the current system which i have been testing on the write side of the application, the write commands traverses though the Command API layer, the command controller layer and the command Handler layer before it ends up in the Event Store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing an Asynchronous System</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/testing-an-asynchronous-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 13:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/testing-an-asynchronous-system/</guid>
      <description>In recent months i have been testing a system built using the CQRS pattern. CQRS stands for Command Query Responsibility Segregation and you can read more about it here.
As a tester, one of the key takeaway for me is that there is a Read side and a Write side to the application. This is very different to the other applications that i have tested in the past where a write operation would NOT be successfully until the data being sent to the application is successfully persisted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geb and Spock: My favourites for test automation</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/geb-and-spock-my-favourites-for-test-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 22:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/geb-and-spock-my-favourites-for-test-automation/</guid>
      <description>So I have used quite a number of tools in my time building test automation frameworks over the years; and in the last 2years i have evaluated a number of these tools and i am becoming more and more opinionated in my choice of tools.
For someone that has used selenium/webdriver and cucumber a lot in the past, i find myself using Geb and Spock these days and it hasnt been much difficulty in switch to these tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never too early to start thinking about your tests</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/never-too-early-to-start-thinking-about-your-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 21:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/never-too-early-to-start-thinking-about-your-tests/</guid>
      <description>This post is spurned by taking a reflection on my journey as a tester and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see how much i have moved from designing large UI test suites to very small UI test suites. For emphasis, the largest test suite had taken over 8 hrs and the smallest has been 3mins of execution time. There are a lot of posts on the internet about how fragile a UI test framework could be and i would expect the next question to be how have you been able to achieve this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copying objects between two different amazon s3 accounts</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/copying-object-between-buckets-on-two-different-amazon-s3-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 15:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/copying-object-between-buckets-on-two-different-amazon-s3-account/</guid>
      <description>I have recently taken on ownership of a website and as part of the migration task i&amp;rsquo;ve had to copy over a few artefacts;I will be posting another blog about what i have learnt from this process.
The website uses Amazon s3 for storing users&amp;rsquo; uploaded photos and document. I was faced with the task of copying these files over to my S3 account. Quite a number of ways to achieve this; but i stumbled on a link which is a python script that copies object between two buckets in the same account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assign AutomationIds to DevExpress ComboxBoxEdit Control</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/assign-automationids-to-devexpress-comboxboxedit-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 13:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/assign-automationids-to-devexpress-comboxboxedit-control/</guid>
      <description>For some time i have been trying to automate a desktop application which uses a lot of DevExpress controls. For someone coming from a web application environment; this was a very difficult task for me as i had no experience of WPF or any of the other custom controls framework out there.
So that i dont have to repeat myself i would post a link to the post i put on the devexpress website but i hope to flesh out a detail blog post sometime in the future so that other people can learn from me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type into a textfield with keypress event disabled</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/type-into-a-textfield-with-keypress-event-disabled/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 08:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/type-into-a-textfield-with-keypress-event-disabled/</guid>
      <description>A colleague asked me how to automate a disabled text-box which has a calendar attached to it. The customer has specified that they want keyboard entries disabled for this text-field, hence every user of the website has to use the calendar drop down.
Previously, this has been automated by using webdriver to type the text into the text box but as it was disabled, this was impossible.
imagine, this is the html for the textbox:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cucumber unicode support</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/cucumber-unicode-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 15:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/cucumber-unicode-support/</guid>
      <description>I ran into a problem today where some french and spanish characters were being displayed strangely.
And this made my test to fail,
After some poking around in google i can across a post that suggested adding
require &amp;lsquo;cucumber/formatter/unicode&amp;rsquo;
to the env.rb and that seem to have sorted the problems i was having.
Hopes this saves you some time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Testing experience using Ant and Jmeter - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/performance-testing-experience-using-ant-and-jmeter-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 15:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/performance-testing-experience-using-ant-and-jmeter-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In my last blog post, i described how i have used jmeter-plugins at my current client site, now i am faced with another problem , i need to be able to run these performance test from command line, in other for these performance tests to be executed in a CI environment such as teamcity.
A quick search brings to light the ant jmeter task which is an ant task for running jmeter test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Testing experience using Ant and Jmeter - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/performance-testing-experience-using-ant-and-jmeter-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 15:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/performance-testing-experience-using-ant-and-jmeter-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Jmeter is a well known open source performance/load testing tool and to be fair it does a lot of stuff really well. if you wants to do some quick performance testing without a whole lots of infrastructure around it then it is great.
I started out my task with jmeter with some objectives:
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt; A tool that i could integrate into a CI tool such as teamcity&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; Meaningful graphs that could be easily interpreted by any one in the team&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; Able to integrate the graphs into teamcity&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; Able to monitor the performance of the website under test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screenshare tool for my trainings</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/screenshare-tool-for-my-trainings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 09:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/screenshare-tool-for-my-trainings/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally i invite people round to my house for testing or automation training which sometimes i find inconvenient. In other situation, someone on other side of town need my help and i cant.
I have recently come across the tool - join.me and it is awesome, it allow mwe to share my screen with people and you can give them control ove your machine as well.
I think this is great !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stumbled on Chrome Net Internal</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/stumbled-on-chrome-net-internal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 16:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/stumbled-on-chrome-net-internal/</guid>
      <description>Sometime i would use my blog as a place to keep interesting stuff for future exploration.
I came across the chrome net internals today and i think it exposes a lot of useful information that might be useful to testers when testing a web application.
To access the chrome net internals, navigate to chrome://net-internals/ on a google chrome browser.
I would be spending some more time in the future exploring this but for now its back to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watir-Webdriver: Website certificate does not come from a trusted source</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/watir-webdriver-website-certificate-does-not-come-from-a-trusted-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 10:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/watir-webdriver-website-certificate-does-not-come-from-a-trusted-source/</guid>
      <description>A colleague came across this problem while executing our acceptance tests.
The issue was related to the fact that the SSL certificate for the site was named differently from the domain on which the test were being executed on .
Hence, we got this error:
&amp;ldquo;xxx.xxx.xxxx uses an invalid security certificate.The certificate does not come from a trusted source.The certificate is only valid for &amp;lt;a id=&amp;ldquo;cert_domain_link&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;ldquo;xxx.xxx.com&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt;xxxx.xxxxx.com&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;The certificate will not be valid until 13-Jul-11 10:28 AM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing acceptance test before development or implementation starts</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/writing-acceptance-test-before-development-or-implementation-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 15:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/writing-acceptance-test-before-development-or-implementation-starts/</guid>
      <description>In my the few years, where i have pushed for testers developers to write acceptance test before development or implementation commences, I&amp;rsquo;ve had testers come up to me say its difficult to achieve this when you dont know what the UI would look like.
This post would attempt to decribe how i have done this in the past and i still do this at the moment.
NB: Ideally i would write my test using page object pattern, if this was a new project, I would start creating page objects</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test automation click might not completely simulate an actual human click</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/test-automation-click-might-not-completely-simulate-an-actual-human-click/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 14:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/test-automation-click-might-not-completely-simulate-an-actual-human-click/</guid>
      <description>I have been working at this client where i am opportuned to use cucumber, watir-webdriver and i came across this problem today. The application i am testing is an e-commerce site and i am writing test for a page on which i click on an item and the item appears on the shopping basket area of the site.
My code look like
[code]
def select_item(item_name) @browser.li(:text =&amp;gt; /#{item_name}/).link(:class_name =&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;addOptions&amp;rdquo;).click Watir::Wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redirecting blogger post to wordpress.com</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/redirecting-blogger-post-to-wordpress-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/redirecting-blogger-post-to-wordpress-com/</guid>
      <description>I moved my blog from the blogger one to wordpress and i wanted to ensure that people that have bookmarked post on my old blog get redirected to the new one on wordpress as i wouldnt be update the old blog anymore.
I found a lot of effort by different people and all the stuff that was suggested using javascript didnt work for me, what i got was regardless of the page you are on my old blogger site, you would be redirected to my homepage on the wordpress site which is not very helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could not start selenium browser session because browserurl does not include &#34;http&#34;</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/could-not-start-selenium-browser-session-because-browserurl-does-not-include-http/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 08:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/could-not-start-selenium-browser-session-because-browserurl-does-not-include-http/</guid>
      <description>I was helping a friend out last weekend, and he was getting an error
java.lang.RuntimeException: Could not start Selenium session: Failed to start new browser session: Error while launching browser
at com.thoughtworks.selenium.DefaultSelenium.start(DefaultSelenium.java:89)
This was strange because looking at his code everything seem to be properly set up, i did some debugging and I discovered that the session in the selenium object was null, this suggested that we weren&amp;rsquo;t initializing the selenium object properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>could not start Selenium session: Failed to start new browser sesion</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/could-not-start-selenium-session-failed-to-start-new-browser-sesion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 08:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/could-not-start-selenium-session-failed-to-start-new-browser-sesion/</guid>
      <description>I have heard people have problems with starting firefox3 while using selenium1.0.x on windows7.
The exact error message is similar to this: java.lang.RuntimeException: Could not start Selenium session: Failed to start new browser session: java.lang.RuntimeException: Firefox 3 could not be found in the path!
Please add the directory containing &amp;ldquo;firefox.exe&amp;rdquo; to your PATH environment
variable, or explicitly specify a path to Firefox 3 like this:
*firefox3c:\blah\firefox.exe
at com.thoughtworks.selenium.DefaultSelenium.start(DefaultSelenium.java:89) I attempted to fix this by putting the path in the environment variable of the windows7 machine and it still did not work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My notes from the selenium conference 2011</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/my-notes-from-the-selenium-conference-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 15:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/my-notes-from-the-selenium-conference-2011/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to attend the selenium conference and loads of good stuff, i must tell you. This post is an attempt to highlight the conference talks/ seminar that i really enjoyed.
 Page Object 101: This was a workshop delivered by Patrick Wilson Welsh and Adam Goucher. Even though I have done a lot of page objects in the past, at a glance i like the way patrick has approached html elements, (wraping each html elements in a class), it feels like writing selenium code in a watir way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails3 &#39;link_to&#39; displays literal HTML on front end</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/rails3-link_to-displays-literal-html-on-front-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 11:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/rails3-link_to-displays-literal-html-on-front-end/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;In the last month, I have been working on a rails3 app and I ran across this interesting problem where I need to create a href link to a another page from my current page.
In my view i have written &amp;lt;%= &amp;ldquo;Please click on this link #{link_to(&amp;lsquo;here&amp;rsquo;, new_house_path)}&amp;rdquo; %&amp;gt;
And interestingly this is displayed as Please click on this link &amp;lt;a href=&amp;ldquo;http://localhost:3000/houses/new&amp;quot;&amp;gt;here&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
on the front end.
Hours of frustration and google searches leads me to doing this: &amp;lt;%= (&amp;ldquo;Please click on this link #{link_to(&amp;lsquo;here&amp;rsquo;, new_house_path)}&amp;ldquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A tester&#39;s reflection on kanban plus BDD</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/a-testers-reflection-on-kanban-plus-bdd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/a-testers-reflection-on-kanban-plus-bdd/</guid>
      <description>Having just finished an engagement with a client where the development practices include kanban and BDD. Kanban for us meant that we give priority to work on the right side of the board. So as a tester, I would rather spend my time doing some manual testing on a story that is in the QA queue, than writing automated acceptance tests for a story in the queue for Acceptance Tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watir: Search for elements on page using multiple attributes</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/watir-search-for-elements-on-page-using-multiple-attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 15:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/watir-search-for-elements-on-page-using-multiple-attributes/</guid>
      <description>I ran into a situation today where i wanted to scan through a page and return a table based on the table matching 3 attributes
Before:
browser.tables.find do |table|
table.class_name == &amp;lsquo;my_class_name&amp;rsquo; and
table.cell(:class, &amp;lsquo;class_1_name&amp;rsquo;).text == &amp;lsquo;some_text_1&amp;rsquo; and
table.cell(:class, &amp;lsquo;class_2_name&amp;rsquo;).text == &amp;lsquo;some_text_2&amp;rsquo;
end
This was taking about 3minutes as there were about 86tables on this page under test. I was worried but the tables on this page was gonna increase with time which meant the time for this stage of the test was bound to increase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement &#39;Select column_name from table_name where condition&#39; in Active Record</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/implement-select-column_name-from-table_name-where-condition-in-active-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 10:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/implement-select-column_name-from-table_name-where-condition-in-active-record/</guid>
      <description>I needed an array from the data contained in a particular database column based on a condition, so i get the array of active record rows:
array_of_rows = TableName.find(:all, :conditions =&amp;gt; {:column_name =&amp;gt; [&amp;lsquo;col_data1&amp;rsquo;,&amp;lsquo;col_data2&amp;rsquo;]})
Then use the array map! function to replace the active record objects with the column_name value
array_of_rows.map!{|item| item.column_name}
Doing some search got me:
array_of_rows = TableName .find(:all,:select=&amp;gt;&amp;lsquo;column_name&amp;rsquo; :conditions =&amp;gt; {:column_name =&amp;gt; [&amp;lsquo;col_data1&amp;rsquo;,&amp;lsquo;col_data2&amp;rsquo;]}).map(&amp;amp;:column_name)
And i like this better, concise &amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Record find by Column Name</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/active-record-find-by-column-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 16:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/active-record-find-by-column-name/</guid>
      <description>In recent days been doing a lot of ruby, which means i tend to use Active Record as well.
I had written some scripts where i was selecting records that matched a criteria such as:
@table1.table2s.select{|e| e.column_name == 1234} but as i need to sort my result and also give some more conditions to filter the data, i need alternatives to this above query and i ended up with the two lines of code below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing the annoying XP Antivirus 2009 OR 2010</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/fixing-the-annoying-xp-antivirus-2009-or-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/fixing-the-annoying-xp-antivirus-2009-or-2010/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;This is not a post directly related to my blog but i am sure there are few people out there that might be facing same issues. In the last one week i had friends whose windows machines have been infected the XP Antivirus 2010, which seems to be a clone of XP Antivirus 2009. The symptoms include that you are get annoyings popups asking you to pay for an antivirus, i hope you have exposed yourself already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blank cells in step tables in cucumber 0.3.11 is represented as nil</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/blank-cells-in-step-tables-in-cucumber-0-3-11-is-represented-as-nil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 23:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/blank-cells-in-step-tables-in-cucumber-0-3-11-is-represented-as-nil/</guid>
      <description>In my current job, I have been doing a lot of acceptance test using Cucumber, Watir and RSpec, obvious all in Ruby. I have been using Cucumber 0.6.x, in which blank cells in the step table are represented by empty string (&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;). This was okay for me until today when i had to use a previous version of Cucumber 0.3.11 due to reasons including compatibility with other projects in the CI build.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>selenium.open timeouts for strange reasons</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-open-timeouts-for-strange-reasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-open-timeouts-for-strange-reasons/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Have you ever been in situations when your selenium RC test times out after the selenium.open command, the page is loaded but selenium just tells you that it has timed out after 30000ms.
I had same problem in Java today when i got the selenium RC 1.0.3 and i fixed the problem by setting the selenium timeout to be &amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo;. so i have done
@BeforeClass
public void setUp(){
selenium = new DefaultSelenium(&amp;ldquo;localHost&amp;rdquo;, 4444, &amp;ldquo;*iexplore&amp;rdquo;, url);</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regex for pipe &#34;|&#34; character</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/regex-for-pipe-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 21:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/regex-for-pipe-character/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to split a string using a regex today and i had this problem
my string of format
A | B | C
My intent was to split this string using the Regex match for &amp;ldquo;|&amp;rdquo;
The regex that worked for me was &amp;ldquo;\|&amp;rdquo; - escaping pipe and then escaping the slash the escapes the pipe</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workaround: Flash selenium test would not run in firefox 3.5 except when the browser mode is *firefoxProxy</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/workaround-flash-selenium-test-would-not-run-in-firefox-3-5-except-when-the-browser-mode-is-firefoxproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 12:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/workaround-flash-selenium-test-would-not-run-in-firefox-3-5-except-when-the-browser-mode-is-firefoxproxy/</guid>
      <description>I looked into flash selenium a few weeks back and i thought it was a great way for me to test certain part of the apps i have been ignoring for some time.
However after knocking up a few test i discovered that my test would not run in my version of firefox (3.5). I got this error:
 INFO - Got result: ERROR: Threw an exception: NPMethod called on non-NPObject wrapped JSObject!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>selenium failed to start browser in iexplore mode when selenium server is started dynamically in code</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-failed-to-start-browser-in-iexplore-mode-when-selenium-server-is-started-dynamically-in-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-failed-to-start-browser-in-iexplore-mode-when-selenium-server-is-started-dynamically-in-code/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;In a previous post, i have written about how i have been starting/ stoping the selenium server dynamically. What i didnt mention was that i was not able to run my tests using Internet Explorer. I got this error
[sourcecode language=&amp;ldquo;java&amp;rdquo;]
11:56:55.272 INFO - Command request: getNewBrowserSession[*iexplore, http://localhost:8080, ] on session null 11:56:55.272 INFO - creating new remote session 11:56:55.381 INFO - Allocated session 688eff769c8b4751b5fb9477bba213f3 for http://localhost:8080, launching&amp;hellip; 11:56:55.397 ERROR - Failed to start new browser session, shutdown browser and clear all session data java.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for a single digit within a string using regex as provided in java api</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/search-for-a-single-digit-within-a-string-using-regex-as-provided-in-java-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/search-for-a-single-digit-within-a-string-using-regex-as-provided-in-java-api/</guid>
      <description>In my current work, i have been writing a lot of test in Java, which obviously means i need to learn a lot more about the Java api, which is good i think?????
Well i needed to match the single digit in this string &amp;ldquo;home-area-1&amp;rdquo; and return this digit. With a quick google i found this piece of code here.
Pattern p = Pattern.compile(&amp;ldquo;a*b&amp;rdquo;);
Matcher m = p.matcher(&amp;ldquo;aaaaab&amp;rdquo;);
boolean b = m.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start the Selenium Server dynamically</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/start-the-selenium-server-dynamically/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/start-the-selenium-server-dynamically/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;I have been working on a test suite in java using testng as the testing framework. I could not have suggested any other test frame work as it allows me to do a lot of configurable setups and teardowns. Yeah am not gonna promote testng anymore, lol.
I could have started using selenium server using a usual batch file that maven could call in one of its targets but i think doing it this way is cleaner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting user extensions when the Selenium Server has been started dynamically</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/setting-user-extensions-when-the-selenium-server-has-been-started-dynamically/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/setting-user-extensions-when-the-selenium-server-has-been-started-dynamically/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;I hope this helps someone someday, I needed to set user extension for a selenium test suite, dynamically in the code as i was starting the Selenium server via same.
public void startSeleniumServer(String port) {
rcc = new RemoteControlConfiguration();
rcc.setPort(Integer.parseInt(port));
try {
seleniumServer = new SeleniumServer(false, rcc);
seleniumServer.start();
} catch (Exception e) {
throw new IllegalStateException(&amp;ldquo;Can&amp;rsquo;t start selenium server&amp;rdquo;, e);
}
}
public void stopSeleniumServer() {
if (seleniumServer != null) {</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium Remote cant start firefox session due to lock on file</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-remote-cant-start-firefox-session-due-to-lock-on-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-remote-cant-start-firefox-session-due-to-lock-on-file/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;I am sure you have on this page, because you have run into problem with selenium not been able to run due to a lock on some profile files. Yes, you know what the error is. I really found useful two blogs here and here. However, inas much as i don not want to repeat what has been saidin the blogs i would paste and quote what i found useful and explain a little bit more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>css selectors in place of xpath for selenium locators</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/css-selectors-in-place-of-xpath-for-selenium-locators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 07:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/css-selectors-in-place-of-xpath-for-selenium-locators/</guid>
      <description>I have always resolved to using xpath whenever i am creating selenium scripts and i need to do locate elements with no &amp;lsquo;id&amp;rsquo;. Well as you would probably know, xpath executes so slow on IE.
For intance i have a test suite that would run in 1hr 30mins on firefox/ safari but the same test suites would take over 4hrs to run to completion on IE.So with the help of a colleagues, i have been using css selectors from last week and i can say this has drastically improved the speed of our test and you would notice too much difference between IE and FF/Safari anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium Test execution speed on Safari vs Internet Explorer</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-test-execution-speed-on-safari-vs-internet-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 19:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-test-execution-speed-on-safari-vs-internet-explorer/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on a selenium test suite that contains about 150 tests. These test would normally take about 4hrs 30mins for it to execute to completion.
I tried to run same tests on Safari today, and it took exactly 1hr 9min. This is such a big difference and i think it is because of the extreme use of Xpath in the test suite. And as it is known thatXpath execute soooo slow in IE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not able to accept meetings in Outlook</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/not-able-to-accept-meetings-in-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2009 15:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/not-able-to-accept-meetings-in-outlook/</guid>
      <description>Need to say i got an error displaying on the invite: This meeting is not in the calendar, it may have been moved or deleted.
Discovered that when i click on the &amp;ldquo;Accept Button&amp;rdquo; for meetings which i have been invited, the Accept button doesn&amp;rsquo;t do anything. The invite sent to me,looks like this :
Doing a bit of google got me this link, and it worked for me</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for Elements in an IFrame on a WebPage to Load</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/waiting-for-elements-in-an-iframe-on-a-webpage-to-load/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 11:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/waiting-for-elements-in-an-iframe-on-a-webpage-to-load/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Waiting for a page to load while writing selenium scripts is pretty straightforward using the
selenium.WaitForPageToLoad(&amp;ldquo;timeout&amp;rdquo;) timeout is time in millisecond.
Sometimes using this command doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, especially when you the whole page is not loaded or reloaded but a popup is loaded in a div on the page. In situation like this i would used the
selenium.WaitForCondition(&amp;rdquo;ScriptToReturnwhich ReturnTrue OrFalse&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;timeout&amp;rdquo;);
e.g. of scripts would be
selenium.WaitForCondition(selenium.browserbot.get CurrentWindow().document
.getElement ById(&amp;lsquo;idOfElement ToBelocated&amp;rsquo;)!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need to get a value of an attribute using selenium</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/need-to-get-a-value-of-an-attribute-using-selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 10:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/need-to-get-a-value-of-an-attribute-using-selenium/</guid>
      <description>I was in this situation when i needed to get the value of an html attribute and i found the selenium.getattribute very handy &amp;hellip;..
Okay the scenario was such that there was an element which is collapsible on the page and the only attibute for that element that indictated the status of the collapsible element was the &amp;lsquo;Class&amp;rsquo;. when the element was collapsed, the value of the class attribute was &amp;lsquo;asleep&amp;rsquo; and when the element was expanded, the value of the class atttribute was &amp;lsquo;awake&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using selenium.GetEval(script)to execute Javascript</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/using-selenium-getevalscriptto-execute-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 08:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/using-selenium-getevalscriptto-execute-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;The task at hand was to navigate through the DOM of a particular webpage and check the
style.display attribute of an object or element if you prefer. There are two elements on this page that displayed either success or failure messages.(msgSuccess and msgFailed)
For perfomance reasons, if previously a successful message was displayed and subsequently the you get a failure message, what the developers of the page did was to amend the style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Explorer doesnt handle xpath to locate images exceptionally well</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/internet-explorer-doesnt-handle-xpath-to-locate-images-exceptionally-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 01:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/internet-explorer-doesnt-handle-xpath-to-locate-images-exceptionally-well/</guid>
      <description>So i have been doing a lot of selenium and the website i am trying to automate test for
doesnt have a lot of element with id, name, or any other HTML attributes that makes selenium testing a bit easier.
So i have been using of xpath, my intent was to click on an image and i have used the src attribute of the image element.
so my original command,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use selenium to create screenshot</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/use-selenium-to-create-screenshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 16:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/use-selenium-to-create-screenshot/</guid>
      <description>I just stunbled across selenium as a tool to take screenshot.
Thuis could be useful for anything.
In my case i used it to take the screenshot of a page just before it throws an error in my selenium test. and that i could have a look and investigate what the problem might have been.
very simple command and the great thing is it can be easily used for screenshots of a page across different browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium and Javascript events</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-and-javascript-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 16:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-and-javascript-events/</guid>
      <description>Have you ver been in situattion when you have typed a value into a text box and you expect a Javascript event to be triggered such as “OnBlur”
Well selenium has a method “FireEvent” which triggers the event for you, but then the trick is you have to strip the “on” and name for the event wouldbe “OnBlur”
I guess abit of example would make more sense, lol. This is what my html look like</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium: Xpath locator can not be used as Option Locator</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-xpath-locator-can-not-be-used-as-option-locator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 13:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-xpath-locator-can-not-be-used-as-option-locator/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;In my new job been doing a lot of selenium and i needed to scroll through the list of
options in a select element and click on a particular options.
i have initially used the browser.DoubleClick
browser.DoubleClick(&amp;ldquo;xpath=//select/option[child::text()=&amp;lsquo;Option_Label&amp;rsquo;]&amp;ldquo;);)
But then this didnt work because selenium doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the functionality to scroll down the select element in other to make my desired option visible.
Looking through the selenium api, i have used another method, which take in two parameters, the select locator and the option locator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorting out devices - Wireless, Inbuilt Microphone on Ubuntu Hardy Heron</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/sorting-out-devices-wireless-inbuilt-microphone-on-ubuntu-hardy-heron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/sorting-out-devices-wireless-inbuilt-microphone-on-ubuntu-hardy-heron/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Faced with the reality of having to hand in my MAC to my former workplace, i decided to buy a Windows machine (HP 6735s Laptop, AMD Athlon TM X2 Dual Core QL-60 1.9Ghz, 4GB memory, 250GB HDD, DVD+-RW SMDL LightScribe writer, Webcam 15.4&amp;rdquo; WXGA (1280 x 800) WLAN Bluetooth Microsoft Windows Vista Home Premium )
and being a MAC - convert, coupled with the numerous negative feedback about Vista. I have installed Ubuntu Hardy Heron on a seperate partition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nant SCP Task: deploy file to a remote server</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/nant-scp-task-deploy-file-to-a-remote-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2008 11:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/nant-scp-task-deploy-file-to-a-remote-server/</guid>
      <description>Actually started the task by attempting to use MSBuild to deploy my application to a remote server.
which would require some secure means, scp, sftp or something of that sort.
The closest i got was SSHSharp which was written by a third party and not thoroughly tested,
i then decided maybe that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the path to go.
Tried to go for Nant instead, and found that Nant core doesnt have a task for secure copy,</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>