<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Application on Sam Adesoga&#39;s Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/tags/web-application/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Application on Sam Adesoga&#39;s Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 12:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/tags/web-application/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Workaround: Flash selenium test would not run in firefox 3.5 except when the browser mode is *firefoxProxy</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/workaround-flash-selenium-test-would-not-run-in-firefox-3-5-except-when-the-browser-mode-is-firefoxproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 12:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/workaround-flash-selenium-test-would-not-run-in-firefox-3-5-except-when-the-browser-mode-is-firefoxproxy/</guid>
      <description>I looked into flash selenium a few weeks back and i thought it was a great way for me to test certain part of the apps i have been ignoring for some time.
However after knocking up a few test i discovered that my test would not run in my version of firefox (3.5). I got this error:
 INFO - Got result: ERROR: Threw an exception: NPMethod called on non-NPObject wrapped JSObject!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium Remote cant start firefox session due to lock on file</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-remote-cant-start-firefox-session-due-to-lock-on-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/selenium-remote-cant-start-firefox-session-due-to-lock-on-file/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;I am sure you have on this page, because you have run into problem with selenium not been able to run due to a lock on some profile files. Yes, you know what the error is. I really found useful two blogs here and here. However, inas much as i don not want to repeat what has been saidin the blogs i would paste and quote what i found useful and explain a little bit more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using selenium.GetEval(script)to execute Javascript</title>
      <link>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/using-selenium-getevalscriptto-execute-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 08:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samblog-a664e.firebaseapp.com/posts/using-selenium-getevalscriptto-execute-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;The task at hand was to navigate through the DOM of a particular webpage and check the
style.display attribute of an object or element if you prefer. There are two elements on this page that displayed either success or failure messages.(msgSuccess and msgFailed)
For perfomance reasons, if previously a successful message was displayed and subsequently the you get a failure message, what the developers of the page did was to amend the style.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>