<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Selenium on Sam Adesoga&#39;s Personal Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/selenium/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Selenium on Sam Adesoga&#39;s Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 08:27:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/selenium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Could not start selenium browser session because browserurl does not include &#34;http&#34;</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/could-not-start-selenium-browser-session-because-browserurl-does-not-include-http/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 08:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/could-not-start-selenium-browser-session-because-browserurl-does-not-include-http/</guid>
      <description>I was helping a friend out last weekend, and he was getting an error
java.lang.RuntimeException: Could not start Selenium session: Failed to start new browser session: Error while launching browser
at com.thoughtworks.selenium.DefaultSelenium.start(DefaultSelenium.java:89)
This was strange because looking at his code everything seem to be properly set up, i did some debugging and I discovered that the session in the selenium object was null, this suggested that we weren&amp;rsquo;t initializing the selenium object properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>could not start Selenium session: Failed to start new browser sesion</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/could-not-start-selenium-session-failed-to-start-new-browser-sesion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 08:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/could-not-start-selenium-session-failed-to-start-new-browser-sesion/</guid>
      <description>I have heard people have problems with starting firefox3 while using selenium1.0.x on windows7.
The exact error message is similar to this: java.lang.RuntimeException: Could not start Selenium session: Failed to start new browser session: java.lang.RuntimeException: Firefox 3 could not be found in the path!
Please add the directory containing &amp;ldquo;firefox.exe&amp;rdquo; to your PATH environment
variable, or explicitly specify a path to Firefox 3 like this:
*firefox3c:\blah\firefox.exe
at com.thoughtworks.selenium.DefaultSelenium.start(DefaultSelenium.java:89) I attempted to fix this by putting the path in the environment variable of the windows7 machine and it still did not work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for a single digit within a string using regex as provided in java api</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/search-for-a-single-digit-within-a-string-using-regex-as-provided-in-java-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/search-for-a-single-digit-within-a-string-using-regex-as-provided-in-java-api/</guid>
      <description>In my current work, i have been writing a lot of test in Java, which obviously means i need to learn a lot more about the Java api, which is good i think?????
Well i needed to match the single digit in this string &amp;ldquo;home-area-1&amp;rdquo; and return this digit. With a quick google i found this piece of code here.
Pattern p = Pattern.compile(&amp;ldquo;a*b&amp;rdquo;);
Matcher m = p.matcher(&amp;ldquo;aaaaab&amp;rdquo;);
boolean b = m.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start the Selenium Server dynamically</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/start-the-selenium-server-dynamically/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/start-the-selenium-server-dynamically/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;I have been working on a test suite in java using testng as the testing framework. I could not have suggested any other test frame work as it allows me to do a lot of configurable setups and teardowns. Yeah am not gonna promote testng anymore, lol.
I could have started using selenium server using a usual batch file that maven could call in one of its targets but i think doing it this way is cleaner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting user extensions when the Selenium Server has been started dynamically</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/setting-user-extensions-when-the-selenium-server-has-been-started-dynamically/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/setting-user-extensions-when-the-selenium-server-has-been-started-dynamically/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;I hope this helps someone someday, I needed to set user extension for a selenium test suite, dynamically in the code as i was starting the Selenium server via same.
public void startSeleniumServer(String port) {
rcc = new RemoteControlConfiguration();
rcc.setPort(Integer.parseInt(port));
try {
seleniumServer = new SeleniumServer(false, rcc);
seleniumServer.start();
} catch (Exception e) {
throw new IllegalStateException(&amp;ldquo;Can&amp;rsquo;t start selenium server&amp;rdquo;, e);
}
}
public void stopSeleniumServer() {
if (seleniumServer != null) {</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium Remote cant start firefox session due to lock on file</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/selenium-remote-cant-start-firefox-session-due-to-lock-on-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/selenium-remote-cant-start-firefox-session-due-to-lock-on-file/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;I am sure you have on this page, because you have run into problem with selenium not been able to run due to a lock on some profile files. Yes, you know what the error is. I really found useful two blogs here and here. However, inas much as i don not want to repeat what has been saidin the blogs i would paste and quote what i found useful and explain a little bit more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium Test execution speed on Safari vs Internet Explorer</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/selenium-test-execution-speed-on-safari-vs-internet-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 19:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/selenium-test-execution-speed-on-safari-vs-internet-explorer/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on a selenium test suite that contains about 150 tests. These test would normally take about 4hrs 30mins for it to execute to completion.
I tried to run same tests on Safari today, and it took exactly 1hr 9min. This is such a big difference and i think it is because of the extreme use of Xpath in the test suite. And as it is known thatXpath execute soooo slow in IE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for Elements in an IFrame on a WebPage to Load</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/waiting-for-elements-in-an-iframe-on-a-webpage-to-load/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 11:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/waiting-for-elements-in-an-iframe-on-a-webpage-to-load/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Waiting for a page to load while writing selenium scripts is pretty straightforward using the
selenium.WaitForPageToLoad(&amp;ldquo;timeout&amp;rdquo;) timeout is time in millisecond.
Sometimes using this command doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, especially when you the whole page is not loaded or reloaded but a popup is loaded in a div on the page. In situation like this i would used the
selenium.WaitForCondition(&amp;rdquo;ScriptToReturnwhich ReturnTrue OrFalse&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;timeout&amp;rdquo;);
e.g. of scripts would be
selenium.WaitForCondition(selenium.browserbot.get CurrentWindow().document
.getElement ById(&amp;lsquo;idOfElement ToBelocated&amp;rsquo;)!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need to get a value of an attribute using selenium</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/need-to-get-a-value-of-an-attribute-using-selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 10:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/need-to-get-a-value-of-an-attribute-using-selenium/</guid>
      <description>I was in this situation when i needed to get the value of an html attribute and i found the selenium.getattribute very handy &amp;hellip;..
Okay the scenario was such that there was an element which is collapsible on the page and the only attibute for that element that indictated the status of the collapsible element was the &amp;lsquo;Class&amp;rsquo;. when the element was collapsed, the value of the class attribute was &amp;lsquo;asleep&amp;rsquo; and when the element was expanded, the value of the class atttribute was &amp;lsquo;awake&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using selenium.GetEval(script)to execute Javascript</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/using-selenium-getevalscriptto-execute-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 08:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/using-selenium-getevalscriptto-execute-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;The task at hand was to navigate through the DOM of a particular webpage and check the
style.display attribute of an object or element if you prefer. There are two elements on this page that displayed either success or failure messages.(msgSuccess and msgFailed)
For perfomance reasons, if previously a successful message was displayed and subsequently the you get a failure message, what the developers of the page did was to amend the style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium and Javascript events</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/selenium-and-javascript-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 16:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/selenium-and-javascript-events/</guid>
      <description>Have you ver been in situattion when you have typed a value into a text box and you expect a Javascript event to be triggered such as “OnBlur”
Well selenium has a method “FireEvent” which triggers the event for you, but then the trick is you have to strip the “on” and name for the event wouldbe “OnBlur”
I guess abit of example would make more sense, lol. This is what my html look like</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium: Xpath locator can not be used as Option Locator</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/selenium-xpath-locator-can-not-be-used-as-option-locator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 13:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/selenium-xpath-locator-can-not-be-used-as-option-locator/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;In my new job been doing a lot of selenium and i needed to scroll through the list of
options in a select element and click on a particular options.
i have initially used the browser.DoubleClick
browser.DoubleClick(&amp;ldquo;xpath=//select/option[child::text()=&amp;lsquo;Option_Label&amp;rsquo;]&amp;ldquo;);)
But then this didnt work because selenium doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the functionality to scroll down the select element in other to make my desired option visible.
Looking through the selenium api, i have used another method, which take in two parameters, the select locator and the option locator.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>